Okay, so in this video then we are going
to discuss the procurement
management plan.
Now the procurement management plan then,
just like any other management plan,
it is one of the subsidiary
management plans
that make up the project management plan.
And again, just like any other of the
management plans, it is
documenting procedures.
It's documenting how.
how the team is going to get goods and
services from outside of the organisation,
how we're going to acquire goods and
services from outside, how procurement
activities are going to be coordinated
with other project activities,
such as a schedule, how we're going to
coordinate based on our activities,
based on our other scheduled activities.
So again, it's always documenting
procedures.
How are we going to determine whether to
outsource the work or do it in-house?
What are all the
considerations for whether
or not to outsource the
worker do it in-house?
So at what point are we
going to determine whether
we should be outsourcing
it or doing it in-house?
So again, all of these procedures are
going to be documented here.
Plus things like, for example,
timetable, as part of this coordination
with other activities, timetable with
other key procurement activities.
So for example, also, as
a simple example, right,
when, does a contract
need to be signed, right?
And when does the work actually need to be
performed in order for us to not go behind
schedule, in order for the vendor to meet
the deadline?
So when's the absolute latest that we
should be signing the contract and latest
that they should be starting the work and
so on and so forth?
So again, how are we going to determine
that?
All of that is documented in the
procurement management plan.
Also things like roles
and responsibilities
and any risk that
you've identified, right?
So who is responsible for the various
procurement activities?
Who is responsible for, say, communicating
with vendors?
Who's responsible for negotiating the
contracts and so and so forth?
And then what risks are we identifying,
right, as we're going
through the procurement?
So again, all of those procedures are
going to be documented here as well.
Also, things like legal considerations,
right?
Not just the fact that we're signing a
contract, obviously that's a legal
document, but even things, even more
things like industry standards,
regulatory requirements and so and so
forth, and all that needs to be considered
as part of our procurement, right,
making sure them that the vendor is going
to perform, right, in a way
that it's meeting industry
standards, regulatory
requirements, and so on and so forth.
So again, when you're building a house,
right, you don't just want to hire anybody
that's, you know, just slap some pieces of
wood together and bricks together and
build your house, no, you want someone
that, you know, knows the building codes
in the municipality or the area that
you're living in and they're going to be
building according to those building
codes, according to the standards,
according to the regulatory requirements
and so and so forth.
Also, we're going to be
reaching out to several
vendors, getting bids
back from several vendors.
So what's the process of obtaining those
bids?
Do we send them an RFP?
Do we send them an
RFI first, before we get
an RFP or is it an RFQ that we're sending?
We're going to talk about these different
bid documents in a separate video.
And then once we have received these bids,
how are we going to compare those bids?
And then how are we
going to determine which one
of these bids is going
to be the best for us?
How are we going to compare all of those?
How are we going to prioritize all of
these different proposals?
So again, those procedures are documented
here.
plus things like multiple vendors we may
have several vendors working on the same
project so again how are we going to
coordinate the work of the several vendors
multiple vendors involved how we're going
to manage some vendors their work is
dependent on other vendors so again how
are we going to manage and control that
and plus also things like currency for
example right how are we going to be
paying them when are we
going to be paying them how often
are we going to be paying
them paying them for their work.
So, normally it's going to be tied to some
kind of milestone.
But what currency?
So you've got vendors that we've hired
here in the US.
They're a US-based
vendor, but then they're
doing work in some of
our foreign subsidiaries.
It's still part of the same
project, but, you know,
which currency are they
actually being paid in?
So, again, all of this needs to be
understood.
all of these procedures.
So any procedure regarding procurement,
regarding your vendors is going to be
documented here in the procurement
management plan.